A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Series AA FA336
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Correspondence, 1882-1957 1920-1948; AA.1; 9 Document Box(es)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - MacFadden, Minnie A., 1920, 1925-1926, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Mauzé, Abby Rockefeller, 1916-1948 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Mauzé, Abby Rockefeller (Transcripts), 1917-1919, 1920, 1923, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - General (N-P) (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - General (Q-R) (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Calendar to the Letters of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller to Lucy Truman Aldrich, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    See also: Folders 47-55.
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1919-1920 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1940-1941, 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich (to Children), 1922, 1933, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 55A)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich (to Lucy Greene), 1901, 1903, 1906, 1912-1915, 1917, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Almira G., 1906 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker, 1932-1934, 1938, 1940-1941, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1912, 1914, 1916, 1918-1921, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, John D. 3rd, 1920-1948 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, John D. 3rd and Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker (Joint Correspondence), 1932-1947 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1906, 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1916-1945, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Transcripts), 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Excerpts), 1927-1935 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1920-1921, 1925, 1928-1934 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1935-1941 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - General (S) (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - General (T) (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - General (V-Y) (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Personal Correspondence - Named - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - "Atlantic Monthly" Letters, 1919, 1935, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Autograph File (Addams-Wooley), 1921-1945 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Condolences Received, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Condolences Received, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Condolences Received, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Domestic Employees, 1930-1931, 1936-1937, 1943, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Domestic Employees, 1949-1951 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Engagement, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Homes, 1949, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Publication of "Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Letters to Her Sister, Lucy" (1957) - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Publication of "Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Letters to Her Sister, Lucy" (1957) - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 0085A)
  - Personal Correspondence - Subject - Publication of "Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Letters to Her Sister, Lucy" (1957) - Family Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 86)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted material.
  - Professional Correspondence - General Office File, 1909, 1911, 1917, 1919-1920, 1926-1929, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Professional Correspondence - General Office File, 1930-1935 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Professional Correspondence - General Office File, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Professional Correspondence - General Office File, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Professional Correspondence - General Office File, 1940-1943 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Professional Correspondence - General Office File, 1945-1948, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Professional Correspondence - Miscellaneous Office Correspondence - Billings, Clare, 1937, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Professional Correspondence - Miscellaneous Office Correspondence - Burns Family, 1937-1941 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Professional Correspondence - Miscellaneous Office Correspondence - Gerard, Raoul, 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Professional Correspondence - Miscellaneous Office Correspondence - Museum Administrators (Various), 1936, 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Professional Correspondence - Miscellaneous Office Correspondence - Paine Mexican Arts Corporation, 1928-1931 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, January-September 1937 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, October-December 1937 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence - Executive Director's Report, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence - Film Library Report, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, January-May 1938 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, June-December 1938 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, January-July 1939 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, January-May 1943 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, June-September 1943 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, October-December 1943 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, January-July 1944 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, August-December 1944 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, January-June 1945 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Professional Correspondence - Museum of Modern Art Correspondence, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 122)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Personal Papers, 1883-1887, 1891-1950, 1954, n.; AA.2; 5 Document Box(es)
  Files are alphabetically arranged by type of material.
  Subseries 2, Personal Papers, brings together an assortment of personal effects which were previously dispersed throughout the collection. There are two volumes of diaries kept by Abby as a young student and debutante in Providence (1892, 1893-1894); seven thick tablets recording social engagements for the years 1894-1898, 1900, and 1901; itineraries, passports, and passenger lists for European trips; invitations; wedding books; and clippings relating to Abby's marriage in 1901, the activities of her six children, and her anti-war and prohibition work.
  - Address Book, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Address Book, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Bills - European Trip, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Bills - Furniture - 740 Park Avenue, 1936-1939 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Biographical Material, 1930, 1937, 1950, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Clippings - Anti-War Work, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Clippings - Art Collections, Exhibits, and Donations, 1922, 1928, 1935-1939 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Clippings - Marriage, 1901 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - Clippings - Prohibition Enforcement, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - Clippings - Rockefeller Family - Mauzé, Abby Rockefeller, 1922, 1934, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - Clippings - Rockefeller Family - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1914-1943 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Clippings - Rockefeller Family - Rockefeller, David, 1940, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Clippings - Rockefeller Family - Rockefeller, John D. 3rd, 1920, 1929, 1932, 1938, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Clippings - Rockefeller Family - Rockefeller, Laurance S., 1926, 1929, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Clippings - Rockefeller Family - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1922-1944, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Clippings - Rockefeller Family - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1932, 1941, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Diaries, 1892, 1893-1894; 2 volumes (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Engagement Books, 1894-1898; 5 volumes (Box 11, Folder 140)
    General note
    Fragile items.
  - Engagement Books, 1900, 1901; 2 volumes (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Exercise Book, 1883-1887 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Exercise Book, 1891 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - European Trips - Miscellaneous Papers, 1894-1902, 1921-1925, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - European Trips - Passenger Lists, 1894-1896, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Gift Book, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Invitations, 1901-1945, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Ledger, 1927-1934 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Lucy Truman Aldrich Kidnapping - Miscellaneous Papers, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Medals, 1921, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Memorials, 1923, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Obituaries, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - Passports, 1894, 1921, 1923, 1925, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Photographs Detached from Scrapbook Pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 0153A)
  - Prayers - Disbound Transcripts, 1920, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - Prayers - Disbound Transcripts, 1920, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - Reading Lists, 1898, 1900, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 156)
  - Scrapbook - "Abby Greene Aldrich, July 5th, 1893, Warwick, R.I." (Box 13, Folder 157)
    Box 18
    See also RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1005.
  - Scrapbooks, Typescript Excerpts from, 1912-1933 (Box 13, Folder 0157A)
  - Speeches of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1918-1924, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - Speeches of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - Speeches - Publicity, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - Wedding Book, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Wedding Gifts, 1901; 2 volumes (Box 14, Folder 162)
    Lists of those who gave gifts.
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Art Collections, 1931-1956, n.d.; AA.3; 8 Document Box(es)
  Files are alphabetically arranged by subject or name of institution.
  Subseries 3, Art Collections, contains disbound albums of photograph inventories of the works of art donated, loaned or sold by Abby Rockefeller from 1931 to 1956. Information pertaining to the original purchase or acquisition of Abby Rockefeller's paintings, sculpture, decorative arts, Japanese and Chinese prints, and American folk art is available in these albums, including provenance, dealer name, purchase price, and date of sale or gift. The verso often holds commentary by the dealer. Major gifts represented in Subseries 3 include those to the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Museum of Modern Art, the Rhode Island School of Design, Colonial Williamsburg, and other major museums such as the Fogg Art Museum at Harvard University, the Art Institute of Chicago, and the Cleveland Museum of Art.
  - Catalog of Objects Sold, 1937-1955 (Box 15, Folder 163)
  - Catalog of Objects Sold, 1937-1955 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - Folk Art Pictures (Not Located), 1939, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 165)
    See also: Williamsburg, Boxes 18-20, folders 192-199.
  - Gifts and Sales, 1937-1954 (Box 15, Folder 166)
  - Gifts to Museums (Disbound Album), ca. 1941 (Box 15, Folder 167)
    Amherst College Averill College Boston Museum Brown University Fiske University Fogg Museum Miscellaneous Museum of the City of New York Philadelphia Museum Phillipse Castle Riverside Church William and Mary College
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Art Institute of Chicago, ca. 1946-1949 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1936, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 169)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Dartmouth College, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Dartmouth College, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Fogg Museum, Harvard University, ca. 1947 (Box 16, Folder 172)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Part I, 1936-1937, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Part II, 1936-1937, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Metropolitan Museum of Art - 1949 Gift, 1936-1939, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Miscellaneous Museums, 1937-1938, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Museum of Modern Art - Summary of Gifts (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Museum of Modern Art - Gifts (A-G), 1935-1938, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 178)
    Arranged by artist's name.
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Museum of Modern Art - Gifts (H-K), 1935-1938, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Museum of Modern Art - Gifts (L-P), 1935-1938, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Museum of Modern Art - Gifts (R-Z), 1935-1938, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Newark Museum, ca. 1937-1940 (Box 18, Folder 182)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Chinese Porcelain, 1954-1955 (Box 18, Folder 183)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Chinese Prints, [1934?] (Box 18, Folder 184)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Japanese Prints - Index of Artists and Prints, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Japanese Prints - Catalog, pp. 1-33, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Japanese Prints - Catalog, pp. 34-57, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Japanese Prints - Catalog, pp. 64-78, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Japanese Prints - Catalog, pp. 80-102, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Miscellaneous, [1934?] (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Rhode Island School of Design - Sculpture, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Gifts, 1931-1935 (Box 19, Folder 192)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Inn, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 193)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Ludwell-Paradise House, ca. 1939 (Box 19, Folder 194)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Ludwell-Paradise House, ca. 1939 (Box 19, Folder 195)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Ludwell-Paradise House, ca. 1939 (Box 19, Folder 196)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Ludwell-Paradise House, ca. 1939 (Box 19, Folder 197)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Miscellaneous Gifts, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 198)
  - Gifts to Nelson A. Rockefeller, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 200)
  - Gifts to Museums and Restorations - Williamsburg - Miscellaneous Houses, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 199)
  - House Inventories and Bills of Goods - Bassett Hall, Williamsburg, 1921, 1937-1938, 1941-1942, 1955, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 201)
  - House Inventories and Bills of Goods - Seal Harbor, Maine, 1936, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 202)
  - House Inventories and Bills of Goods - 740 Park Avenue, New York City, 1938-1939, 1941-1942 (Box 20, Folder 203)
  - Japanese Prints (Box 20, Folder 204)
    "Contents of Boxes" "Index of Artists" "The Philadelphia Museum Bulletin," Volume XLII, No. 211, November 1946
    See also folders 205-211.
  - Japanese Prints - Boxes 1-2b (Box 20, Folder 205)
  - Japanese Prints - Boxes 3-4b (Box 20, Folder 206)
  - Japanese Prints - Boxes 5-8 (Box 21, Folder 207)
  - Japanese Prints - Box 9 (Box 21, Folder 208)
  - Japanese Prints - Boxes 10-11 (Box 21, Folder 209)
  - Japanese Prints - Boxes 12-18 (Box 21, Folder 210)
  - Japanese Prints - Boxes 19-23, 29-33 (Box 21, Folder 211)
  - Japanese Prints - Inventory of Prints at 740 Park Avenue, ca. 1938 (Box 21, Folder 212)
  - Japanese Prints - Various Prints, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 213)
  - Loans to Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 214)
  - Miscellaneous Items Not Located, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 215)
  - Modern Pictures Sold, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 216)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Philanthropy Files, 1917-1953, 1957; AA.4; 4 Document Box(es)
  This subseries is alphabetically arranged by subject.
  Correspondence documenting Abby's philanthropies, especially her World War I relief work, the Y.M.C.A. Housing Committee work, the Grace Dodge Hotel, and the Bayway Community Center is housed in Subseries 4, Philanthropy Files, together with annual benevolence reports (1917-1924, 1935-1943) prepared by Arthur W. Packard. As used in this subseries, the term "contribution" generally refers to a monetary gift made to an institution or organization; the term "donation" typically refers to a monetary gift made to an individual.
  - Bayway Community Center - Correspondence of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1919-1928, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 217)
  - Bayway Community Center - Correspondence of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1936-1940, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 218)
  - Bayway Community Center - Correspondence of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1943-1953, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 219)
  - Bayway Community Center - Files of Arthur W. Packard, 1937-1944 (Box 23, Folder 220)
  - Bayway Community Center - Files of Arthur W. Packard, 1937-1944 (Box 23, Folder 221)
  - Bayway Community Center - Printed Material, 1942-1943, 1953, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 222)
  - Bayway Community Center - Survey of Community House Activities, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 223)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (A-C) (Box 24, Folder 224)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (D-F) (Box 24, Folder 225)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (G-L) (Box 24, Folder 226)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (M-Na) (Box 24, Folder 227)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (New York Cancer Institute - New York Osteopathic) (Box 24, Folder 228)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (New York Skin and Cancer Hospital - P) (Box 24, Folder 229)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (R-T) (Box 24, Folder 230)
  - Benevolences - Appeals Letters (V-Y) (Box 24, Folder 231)
  - Benevolences - Contributions, 1935-1940 (Box 24, Folder 232)
  - Benevolences - Contributions, 1941-1943 (Box 24, Folder 0232A)
  - Benevolences - Contributions, 1944-1946 (Box 24, Folder 0232B)
  - Benevolences - Contributions, 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 0232C)
  - Benevolences - Closed Folder (Box 24, Folder 232)
    Material Removed from Folder 232C
  - Benevolences - Correspondence of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1912-1921, 1940, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 233)
  - Benevolences - Declinations (Samples), 1940 (Box 25, Folder 234)
  - Benevolences - Donations, 1936-1939 (Box 25, Folder 235)
  - Benevolences - Donations, 1940-1943 (Box 25, Folder 0235A)
  - Benevolences - Donations, 1944-1947 (Box 25, Folder 0235B)
  - Benevolences - Donations and Presents, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 0235C)
  - Benevolences - Closed Folder (Box 25, Folder 235)
  - Benevolences - Memoranda, 1941-1948 (Box 25, Folder 236)
  - Benevolences - Reports, 1917-1924, 1935-1943 (Box 25, Folder 237)
  - Roadside Improvement Program - Scrapbook, 1904-1935 (Box 25, Folder 238)
  - Wayside Improvement Program, 1927 (Box 26, Folder 239)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) - Grace Dodge Hotel, 1922-1935 (Box 26, Folder 240)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) - Housing Committee of the War Work Council, 1917-1919 (Box 26, Folder 0240A)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) - Housing Committee of the War Work Council, 1920-1923, 1926, 1929, 1932-1934, 1941-1944, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 0240B)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Aldrich/Greene Family Papers, 1858-1949, n.d.; AA.5; 1 Document Box(es)
  Records are alphabetically arranged by type of material.
  Subseries 5 contains the Aldrich and Greene Family Papers (1858-1949). The series consists largely of the correspondence (1860-1913, n.d.) received by Abby's mother, Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich, who, though born in Preston, Connecticut, was raised by the Duty Greene family of Providence. Most of the correspondence is from the Greene and Pierce families, Providence friends, and four of her children, Lucy (1885, 1887-1902), Stuart (1885, 1887), William (1885, 1887, 1900), and Abby (1885-1913). There is one folder of correspondence from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (1901-1907, 1907-1911) and two letters from Laura Spelman Rockefeller (1901, 1903).
  - Account Book and Miscellaneous Papers of Nelson W. Aldrich, 1884-1885, 1867 (Box 27, Folder 241)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - General - Family and Friends, 1860-1902, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 242)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - Aldrich, Lucy Truman, 1885, 1887-1902 (Box 27, Folder 243)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - Aldrich, Stuart M., 1885, 1887 (Box 27, Folder 244)